## KIA ORA, I AM

## TISHA NAICKER.

### 2ND YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am in my second year of a Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) degree specialising in Software at the University of Auckland. My love and incredible passion for coding has led me to look for internship opportunities that utilise knowledge specific to my software engineering career. A little bit about me, I enjoy being creative through drawing and painting, and I would go to an escape room regularly if I could because I love problemsolving to escape them!

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

I am proficient in Java, C, HTML, CSS, MATLAB programming languages. Here are a few projects I have done:

- With Java I created the game Black Jack where I used Factory and Strategy patterns for the bots and dealer. I also incorporated Artificial Intelligence by changing the dealer strategy in runtime based on player scores. Another Java project I did was create an online order system for a Burger restaurant where the user could place an order, the system will display cart, total price, give discounts, suggest user to switch to combo and calculate total time needed for order to be ready. I also created data structures using Java such as Linked List, Stacks and Queues and used this to create Breadth First Search and Depth First Search. In all these projects I used Object Orientated Programming.
- C project where I created the Container Yard game effectively and efficiently. The game is where a container is stuck between other containers of different lengths and orientation and the objective is to take it out.
- With HTML and CSS I have created my website portfolio (linked below) and multiple websites in high school where I creatively designed wireframes, developed and iterated my web design and functionality.
- MATLAB project about Visual Cryptography where I successfully encoded and decoded hidden messages in an image.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SALES ASSISTANT | SMIGGLE, MANUKAU

OCT 2020 - FEB 2022

- Successfully interacted and helped the customers to benefit their needs.
- Ensured I used excellent customer service skills such as welcoming, being a good listener to their needs, interests and always doing right by them.
- Actively and consistently helped meet our weekly sale targets.
- Efficiently and effectively met average transaction value and unit per transaction goals.

#### TUTOR | NUMBERWORK'NWORDS, HOWICK

OCT 2020 - DEC 2020

- Successfully tutored students ranging from primary to high school.
- Actively aided the development of the student's numeracy skills by explaining thoroughly.
- Effectively provided a set of tools and strategies to improve their numeracy skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (HONOURS) SPECIALISING IN SOFTWARE**

University of Auckland | Jan 2021 - Present (Graduation Year: 2024)

- Cumulative GPA of 8.42
- Part II: A+ for Object-Oriented Programming, A+ for Software Engineering Theory, A+ for Computer Engineering, A+ for Mathematical Modelling 2
- Part I: A+ for Introduction to Engineering Computation and Software Development



https://tnai255.github.io/TishaNaickerPortfolio/













# TISHA NAICKER

### 2ND YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Worley Professional Engineering Scholarship Recipient (2022)
- University of Auckland Top Achiever Scholarship (2021)
- Botany Downs Secondary College DUX (2020)

#### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

- · Critical Thinking: My Engineering degree and the subjects I took in high school required a high level of critical thinking, such as analysing and problem-solving.
- Creativity: My favourite hobbies are art visual, digital, and dancing.
- · Teamwork: My prior job was heavily team focused, and my past leadership roles in school have all been team oriented.
- Communication: Growing up in church and having leadership roles in school has equipped me to build connections with people from various demographics.
- IT skills: I completed four years of Digital Technology in school, where most of my grades were excellences.
- Organisation: My grades are a product of being highly organised with my study habits and techniques.
- · Proficient in MS Office.
- Full License Driver

#### **CO-CURRICULAR EXPERIENCE**

In high school, I was in a leadership role where I was responsible for running and organising assemblies as well as being in charge of the academic committee. I participated in Indian and African dance, played Netball, mentored a student through COVID and was involved in the math, outreach and environmental committees. In church, I am part of the technology and creative team where I am in charge of audio and visual some Sundays and I have helped with mentoring young people.

#### **INTERESTS**

In my spare time, I love to draw, paint, and do digital art! I really enjoy making handcrafted keepsakes, so these are my favourite outlets to do so. I love my Fijian Indian culture and embrace it by giving importance to staying connected to my cultural roots such as by speaking Hindi. Being a women in engineering can be hard but I am enormously proud to be part of that minority, so I go to various Women in Engineering events to meet individuals like me! I am also heavily involved in my c3 church community and actively do volunteer work as a part of that.

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

I am bilingual, so I am fluent in Hindi and English! Hindi being my native language.

#### REFEREES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST



https://tnai255.github.io/TishaNaickerPortfolio/









